[Music]
welcome to another episode of voice club
and again to a conversation that centers
on the relationship between psychedelics
and society today I'm speaking with Nick
Wallace Nick is the founder of in
psychedelia org co-founder of the
Australian psychedelic Society and also
a presenter of in psychedelia on Mel
Burns 3c our community radio station in
psychedelia is a platform for Melbourne
psychedelic culture and focuses on the
controversial crossroads of psychoactive
my states and society some core
objectives of the Australian psychedelic
society are to provide educational
resources to the psychedelic community
to improve safety well-being and promote
best practice and to support psychedelic
research to increase benefits to society
thank you for joining me now let's hear
from Nick watts
thank you very much for coming in thank
you for having me down here you've
conducted many more interviews and I
have oh it's been a while well you know
you have people on 3cr
I've listened to a few of those
conversations Oh interesting yeah yeah
yeah well I mean I've just had Peter
just ed on the podcast I spoke to him
last year but I know you've had him on
previously as well and I did watch that
when he linked it to me and he's always
an interesting guy to listen to very
interesting yeah it was an interesting
conversation but given that in a sense
this is well I don't imagine this to be
an interview it's not precisely what I
go into these things with the mind to do
but given that the boot is slightly on
the other foot here if you could ask
yourself a question to get yourself
primed I mean because I what is it that
has you at the moment something you're
working on that's just really
captivating you and you're trying to
figure out I have an obsession of sorts
and that obsession has been for a long
time around what abstract is what what
is this the abstract well because I
think that most of the world we live in
most of the day-to-day world is actually
abstract and we don't realize it there
was this great video I found on YouTube
that people might have come across
before called I think it was something
from reddit but a guy did a vocal thing
of it called kill theory okay and and it
was just a silly little story about
hamburgers and you eat a hamburger but
but the concept of it was that there are
different levels so level 1 or q1 is
this reality right here that I can see
in front of me that is what my sensory
array picks up right so all of my senses
not just a 5 we usually think I'll be
all the senses that's Q level 1 right
but you'll level 2 is like when you can
talk about your friend who's outside of
your sensory array now about something
that they're doing and then level 3
might be talking about what you think
they're thinking about even though
they're not even gonna say you know so
it goes on and on grows in complexity
and we do these tasks all the time
there's this abstraction task and I've
been obsessing over this because I think
that we have increasingly come into a
more and more abstract world as we have
become more connected so as we have
lowered the
boundaries between each other it's
actually put up these new boundaries
that are invisible to us that are these
sort of neuro-linguistic sort of
boundaries these strange boundaries that
are hard to describe hard to see cuz
they're somewhere in between the
language and how our brains work and how
our culture works and how our
communities operate and I'm obsessing
over this question and I've been getting
into I'm listening to a another podcast
at the moment called a culture that's a
culture and just getting into how that
discourse works I suppose what the
occult discourse is and a lot of it does
seem to be around this question of
abstraction of what the nature of
reality actually is and of what what we
are what I am what you are in this
reality thing that were in mm-hmm
yeah well that's a difficult one whom do
you think that do you think that so
let's go back I think
anatomically modern human beings it's
roughly two hundred thousand years ago
of course we were just a little bit
different before then and going back but
let's just say fifty thousand years ago
when we're well and truly hunters and
gatherers do you think that we were
living in a world that was more real
then in a sense or do you rather think
that that same process of abstraction
was happening it's just it wasn't at
such a degree of complexity yeah
option B yeah I think it's always being
a process of I don't think this is just
happening to us humans I think that it
does happen to other creatures it's just
hard to know to what extent it's
happening and it's it does seem to be
certainly unique in us and I think it's
got a lot to do with a frontal lobe and
our ability to store information recall
it and and this process yeah no I do
think that we probably have to spend
quite a long time really getting clear
on on everything we mean that might go
into a conversation to unpack something
like this but I do think that really
that hits at perhaps one of its it's
definitely one of the core difficulties
with being a human being at the moment
of course there's a question of truth
wrapped up in there that there's a
question of what is most real I mean
that's essentially what we're talking
about here is like if the necessity of
our being is experiencing iterative
moments of abstraction at least in part
then
do we have to find the right system of
abstractions that serves that process of
making abstractions are we trying to
serve something more real behind it are
we are we trying to serve the human race
as distinct from other animal species or
other organisms perhaps the universe
itself like to what extent are we
connected with some sort of source of
reality if we can making this
distinction between something abstract
but then something more real behind it
so yeah it's that disjunction that
people feel you know it's only a stone's
throw away to the meaning or lack
thereof people might feel in their lives
and the challenge that science might
have hit up against or posed to religion
well perhaps it's that we're thinking
about I hate this term but I'm going to
use it because I think it does describe
an issue that we see this term scientism
and I really hate this term because I
often see see it used in a way for
people that don't understand don't
refuse to even try to understand
something and they'll just dismiss it
with another silly word but I think what
it's trying to describe is dogmatic
tendencies and dogmatic tendencies
aren't bound to religion or they're not
bound to one type of way of seeing the
world and I think that within science
the way that it's practiced in the world
we do get a lot of dogmatic type
tendencies where people or groups or
universities become locked into a
paradigm a way of thinking about
whatever it happens to be where they
won't be able to look outside of that
and these are these are the questions
that we're really circling around a lot
at the moment it seems that I mean as
you were saying before we have this this
question about what is truth what is
reality and this has been turned upside
down at the moment it seems I really
think that watching the whole Trump
s-capepod which I don't quite understand
still yet but I'm I'm very interested in
watching it play out is this people just
rejecting Authority sources that have
been built up in liberal democracies
across the world for quite some time so
the universities the Democratic
structures themselves the institution's
the - you know all of the hard work of
maintaining society and people
just gone because they're feeling
disconnected and detached from these
things and I think these institutions
and organizations are doing the same
back they are disconnected and detached
from the people that they're meant to be
serving as well yeah they've got a that
they think that they know best they're
there they're getting stuck into the
dogmatic tendencies of Sciences this
obsession with data thinking the data is
the world rather than a reflection of a
small part of it and I mean even I've
been thinking a lot in my drug policy
and advocacy work we talk a lot about
evidence-based or evidence-informed
policy but even that phrase is sort of
wrapped up in assumptions about what
sort of evidence we're looking at about
what it actually implies what are the
goals we're looking for because almost
anybody can twist art especially people
that are really good with this stuff can
twist their data to say anything that
they wanted to say and make it look
convincing to other people especially if
you've got good graphics people and
sound people in PR and suddenly the
truth is yours to mold as you wish it's
always been that way but it's a large
scale now and people seem to have thrown
off more egalitarian efforts for more
selfish efforts it seems that's
fascinating there's so many different
places or levels at which to pick up
this tension because I do think it's
it's totally right to recognize a
disconnect between you know institutions
and certain groups of people and between
groups of people because they take
different views on what that initial
disagreement is about and but then
there's also disagreements as we're
talking about here with scientism is
mostly used as a pejorative word I've
read decent defenses of it there's um
you know at least very articulate and
well put together philosophically
rigorous defenses of it for example
there's a book called everything must go
by James lady moon and Don Ross and you
know they put together a defense of the
historical scientific method but also
how properly understood that actually is
serving our most reliable means that
arriving of truth even now but it's so
difficult to do because what physics
actually tells us is so strange and
confusing that in
order to actually rigorously try and
integrate that constraining nature of
physics on to the rest of our philosophy
you know it's something that for them at
least most philosophers don't even do
properly and so therefore there's whole
swathe of analytic philosophy that is
within the institution is part in some
sense and we haven't described how this
might be but might be part of some sort
of problem but even they are there's
problems within and so how I've been
most I think engaged with this
difficulty about the nature of truth in
my own work has largely been to do with
this kind of scientist in this in the
work I've written about I don't I don't
quite put it as an over infatuation with
data although I think that's actually
quite a decent characterization of it
obviously we could be more acute from a
process philosophy perspective it might
be a sort of an ignorance of the fact
that you are working within an axiomatic
framework of fixations that have somehow
been thundered from in an experiential
duration and perhaps a real qualitative
source of meaning and perhaps perhaps
him that was quite the sentence so
there's there's a difficulty here if you
really want to try and bring science and
mysticism or science and religion
together you have to find some sort of
paradigm in which the same team is there
for everybody to be a part of and that
hat team has to be grounded in the same
love for the same sort of truth and I
think that truth needs to be something
like fundamentally a sort of truth about
life but that is taking a very you know
is taking a metaphysical position that
might be entirely disagreed with by by
but these are the these are interesting
questions amid a metaphysical ones and
unfortunately it feels like a lot of the
the space for metaphysical discussions
has been dominated by religions that
want to separate the world into good and
bad black and white Abrahamic religions
at least the more orthodox someone's
which is most of them have this
separation this division this world
divided that we are living in some you
know some damned world and if we just
pray to whatever then we'll get to go to
the the good
afterwards it's it's a distorted
thinking it's like I understand that
people don't like using these sorts of
terms that I'm about to use in this
context but I literally think it's a bit
of a schizophrenic drift that we've gone
that there's a material world and
there's this there's this other world
this magical world that underlies it but
the way that I see it is it's one in the
same world it's all around us it this is
the magical world already we never left
Eden in the first place you know if you
want biblical references references in
there there was never a fall none of
this stuff happened in the way that the
sort of narrative plays out and I think
that that division ends up putting us in
a lot of strife because I think that
division has seeped into how some of our
scientific institutions operate that
they're trying to be quite hard and
materialistic and reductionistic to such
an extent that they're forgetting that
it's the connections between things that
make a lot of these things happen that
sometimes you need the and we're seeing
it more now but you need
interdisciplinary and the
multidisciplinary approaches to answer
some of these difficult questions you
can't just keep making it smaller and
smaller and smaller and finding the
building blocks of things because
sometimes the building block only works
in context with other things and I think
that approach has modeled some people
and I think that's where this scientism
term comes from the reason why I hate it
it's because usually gets used by like
flat-earthers or other ridiculous
conceived just broken their brain on
these really absurd sort of questions I
understand sort of the philosophical
discourse desired by it to try and like
though what do I actually know but I
think there's a far better ways to do it
then go down a flat earth Facebook group
black hole but when those people come up
against and I when I've spoken to
friends of mine who go down these and
conspiracy black holes they speak about
getting frustrated with people that have
this very hard materialistic view that
thinks that everything is sort of
inanimate apart from yourself but
there's something special about the self
and I'll sort of almost have like a
thinking of soul or maybe they just
think that the odds just people that say
it's justice or just that you know
and I mean maybe this is a deviation
onto another topic that we're going to
talk about that one of my greatest
frustrations in trying to talk about
altered experiences through psychoactive
chemicals is when people are like ah but
that's just your brain on drugs you know
like what a dismissal of a phenomena
that is clearly intriguing yeah and it's
because the question is not as simple as
oh you put the bird in the drug
interacts with this molecule and then
that you know that's all it is and it's
like no it's not all it is I am met and
spoke with like probably alien morphing
multi-dimensional rainbow creatures like
that is not described by that chemical
interaction yeah so yep we'll get to
those bubbly rainbow aliens in a second
but you know what just occurs to my mind
there and it's something that I do think
about a bit is that well so two things
one if there's a domain in which you can
understand the response people have to
just sideline psychedelics to try and
dismiss them as something not only
dismiss them as something that could
lead to I want to say a greater truth
but important discoveries about our own
minds and perhaps the universe itself at
a really metaphysical level but the fact
is that that engaging with them we don't
have really we have the beginnings of an
appropriate paradigm in which to try and
understand and relate to that experience
and it makes sense to me that there are
certain individuals who are more
constituted to be able to deal with that
to begin with the reality is it's not
everybody is as inquisitive as other
people yeah absolutely and we have to be
able to put things in categories if we
want to move on right and so you can
totally understand people's fear
response to something that is so
fundamentally alien that our culture had
to entirely outlaw it and if you do have
that experience not only kind of not
only is the dark side there as palpably
on the other side of the curtain always
ready to pierce itself out if you're not
even if you are properly paying
attention and trying to deal with it the
fact is you're only paying attention to
the fact that you may have to deal with
it it doesn't
anywhere and you know there's a lot of
difficult things to pass with it but
it's hardly the tale of a proud and and
successful and brave human race to just
throw difficult and strange and scary
things aside forever the fact is we are
here because we have the ability to
confront things and learn things from
them and so of course that is a disaster
a strategy merely to sideline it but
certainly you can understand why some
people had almost no other recourse than
to just than to just bracket bracket it
off so I mean when it comes to trying to
talk to people who have not had much
experience at all with psychedelics and
may have just been fed what really are
for the most part a bucket of lies about
not only the dangers and there are
dangers but they're not the sort of
dangerous that might be spoken about
you're not gonna think you're a glass of
orange juice that can't sit down anymore
because you might just tip out and then
you'll be dead haha
it's absurd well you know how that has
happened let us know oh god I mean this
from a man who was just having
experiences with that with rainbow
aliens it's all manner of phenomena is
out there but about how do you how do
you find talking to someone who has
those psychological barriers of
resistance there have you ever found any
success in being able to have a
productive conversation with someone
like that as time has gone by I've
learnt more and more I engage in a lot
of unproductive conversations and I'm
sure a lot of people listening right now
probably have that same experience I
think Facebook has done done a scene on
that a little bit you get in there on
Facebook yeah yes less so now because
I'm realizing that what we do when we
engage somebody with a novel idea
that they already have a preconceived
idea about is that no matter no matter
how much you wanted to bait it and you
think you're logical and being rational
and you're using evidence and blah blah
blah it actually in grains their idea
more because it creates this this
defensive dynamic and people put up a
wall and people don't want to discuss it
further because they've already got this
pre concern
notion of it so it's highly emotionally
charged especially on emotionally
charged issues and drugs are one of
those emotionally charged issues yeah
because of a hundred years of also
prohibition and the sorts of rhetoric
that goes out there so to engage people
I've I'm trying to think I'm trying to
think of a good example so I mean I
speak with my parents about this sort of
thing
neither of them mum is not even a
drinker for example she's not somebody
that imbibes in these things at all but
she does have a framework of you know it
looked into and experimented with like
wicker and these sorts of things before
so she's got a minor framework and she's
a writer so she's got that kind of
framework that I can start to frame
discussions around what the psychedelic
experience is to her with my dad he
apparently he had tried something many
many years ago when he was a you know
teenager or 20s or whatever so he's got
a mild framework again but he didn't go
far he saw some bad things with his
friends so that's he's you know that's
what he's seen and I know a lot of
people also have that experience they
might have seen some strange experiences
I think this happens a lot at festivals
where people will decide to take a
psychedelic substance LSD or whatever at
the first festival that they go to and
this is the first psychedelic experience
they're gonna have and this is a
combination for disaster yeah like if
somebody doesn't understand what the
psychedelic space is going to be like I
mean people can have great times too but
I've seen plenty of people not have
great times and then them and their
friends decide oh well you know LSD
makes you mad and they'll make a very
emotionally charged decision based on
that one experience that one
ill-informed and arguably you know if
somebody had had have talked to them
about it they was gone hey maybe try it
at home with like a good friend and you
know so you need to push past barriers
that might actually be ingrained because
somebody had a bad experience once or
saw a friend with a bad experience or
those sorts of tau so it's highly
emotional so to get past that I suppose
I mean just being honest but not pushy
not being a preacher not trying to
dominate conversations with stories of
psychedelia you don't want to be a
psychedelic zealot we've had those
before in the past
I think that is what undid part well
that's one part one small part of the
puzzle that undid what happened in the
original countercultural movement in the
US and in Australia in 60s and 70s but
there was a lot of other stuff going on
as well but speak your truth quietly and
clearly I guess and listen listen to
others about these things and and if
it's an emotional discussion which it's
inevitably going to be stop trying to go
for evidence and facts and give them
this journal in that journal but if it
is that kind of discussion give them
that and you can probably have two parts
of that discussion like at different
times with the same person say every now
and then you can give them some evidence
and say hey check out this article if
that's the way that they want to engage
and then give them the emotional story
of our well here's this experience that
I had or you know my friend was talking
about this later so it's it's it's hard
and it's a longer journey than a face
book no that's a very great answer so I
was just about to go and introduce what
you're doing with 3cr or what have you
because I have a question that sort of
follows on from it but maybe maybe you
should maybe you should tell us what
three CCR's about and what you're
currently involved in that yeah so 3cr
is one of Milburn's community radio
stations I've actually come to find that
Australia has a really vibrant community
radio community culture which doesn't
exist in a lot of other countries to
this extent so that's something we
should be thankful for 3cr is sort of
traditionally your activist tea lefties
sort of nest and they're rabble rousers
by by tradition I suppose so I'll just
sort of contextualized with this I
started doing a radio show called sorry
a podcast called in psychedelia right
back in 2012 and I did a few episodes of
it and then a life happened and I had to
do other stuff and I decided I wanted it
on the radio but the broadcasting
services act in Australia stipulates
that you are not among other things you
are not allowed to be seen to promote
illicit drug use okay right so what does
that mean what is it to promote illicit
drug use well in some contexts some
people have tried to frame an honest
discussion about positive negative
effects about an experience as well
that's promoting drug use so we had to
be very careful in and there's a line
that we still have to walk we still have
to be very careful this is also by the
way why most newspaper TV and radio
stories you see
drugs will almost inherently have a
negative bias because they're they're
basically held to that by not only the
broadcasting Services Act that I often
buy their own internal rules and
regulations too but what we want to do
with in psychedelia is is push this and
be radically honest I suppose and start
telling the stories of the community of
people who take drugs which guess what
is most people in this country most
people in the world in fact I don't
think you can escape drugs if we see
that term as broadly as it ought to be
applied yeah totally drugs are a useful
thing drugs are a dangerous thing you
know both of those things are in that
most things have that conundrum inherent
within them and I don't think the answer
is to go I'll well throw it out you know
we put it off to the corner it's too
scary we need to talk about it so that's
what I've been doing on on three CRS is
talking about a wide variety of issues
like I'd love to my passion is obviously
with psychedelics but there's a lot of
other stuff to talk about around drug
policy in Victorian in Australia
especially around things like the the
big issues a sort of pill testing
roadside drug testing the sniffer dogs
the medically supervised injecting
Center medical cannabis so these sorts
of issues is a ray of issues that we we
keep our eye on and keep watching I also
do a Wednesday breakfast show just
because I don't know I hate sleep I
guess so yeah that's fun too we just
talk about we do breakfast show stuff
but it's how can people tune into that
3cr in Melbourne is on 8:55 a.m. and on
digital for anyone that owns a digital
radio I just went out and bought one for
20 bucks from came up the other day by
the way it's interview want one and
that's just called 3 CR Digital but it's
also streamed at 3 Seattle okay you and
you can also find podcasts when I can
get them up which as you're probably
finding out it's a lot of work to get
these things done oh yeah good time big
time so I'm slowly getting the well the
picture of what might be driving you but
I wonder could you tell me what so many
different ways we could go at this but
just very broadly what's driving you and
then how is that hitting the world in
terms of the actions you're taking is it
occurring at this more trying to affect
some sort of systemic
change their because you know talking
about legal issues here talking about
how psychedelics affect society
community radio is certainly more seems
like slightly more part of traditional
culture than podcasts are for instance
so you you're hitting up against you're
trying to hit up against where the
actual concrete walls are to having
these discussions and you're trying to
see where the appropriate places are to
try and move the move the border a
little bit in a way that makes dialogue
and possible it seems to be the sense
I'm getting so what's driving you and
then how's that hitting hitting the
world
I think I'm driven by this obsession
with again like the abstract the mystery
in the world that that there isn't an
answer out there and that doesn't matter
that's fine but there's lots of answers
it's just that every answer is a new
question and and something about like
the first time I had a psychedelic
substance which was mushrooms I've eaten
some mushrooms and ended up rolling
around in the bush or whatever but I
just had this this thought over and over
and over and I think it's really stuck
with me that I was at this this edge
point and just over and over thinking
I'm at the edge and it was this kind of
maniacal kind of realization like why
die as I'm at the edge of I don't even
know what I'm talking about even but I
think that as time has progressed that
edge feels like where we are at all
times we're always at the you know the
precipice of the moment we're never in
the past or the future were always
slinging through this moment moment
moment moment over and over and over and
it's it's building up so I obsess about
these kind of stuff and and that kind of
drives this desire to shift the way and
I'm dream and be here so I try not to
look too like delusional grandeur vision
we need to the world is not going to
continue operating on the the
capitalists dream and I don't want to
sound like a you know socialist nut bag
here I'm but the the capitalist regime
is over it's done it's done it's done
its job I think in the way that it
currently operates and we need to change
how we structure this world and I don't
think that can happen until we change
what we are
I think we
might be seeing the process of evolution
happening right in front of us that we
are not I mean what is it to be human
now is it is our technology part of us
in some ways I mean if we can think of
language as a sort of primal technology
the ability for me to transmit what's
going on inside my brain into your brain
is pretty incredible but now we can do
this in this like highly engrossing ful
fully sensory engrossing way with with
virtual reality and things like that but
I don't think we quite I think we're
gonna make a lot of mistakes if we don't
think hard about what it is we're doing
how how we structure things and if we're
leaving something out of the picture
yeah I think we probably are leaving
something out of the picture because
we're going round and round and there's
some in this value game that we're you
know the scarcity game where in many
places scarcity doesn't exist so we have
to artificially create an in which case
not the Helloween why are we doing that
we don't trust each other and why don't
we trust each other and I understand why
we don't trust each other because I mean
you were just telling me a story earlier
about a bunch of guys who had stolen a
bunch of guns just quite near you and
you know people are up to up to strange
things but I don't know I don't know
what the answer to this isn't but I do
think that it's important that we bring
the psychoactive the altered worlds back
into the equation that we stopped
stigmatizing these altered states that
we actually start to try and understand
why they happen not just the the drug
experiences - but my favorite authors I
suppose is Oliver Sacks who has written
fantastic things about all sorts of
strange altered states that people have
had from brain damage or a mental health
issue of one kind or another but that he
felt it was very helpful for him to have
taken a variety of psychoactive
substances because he felt like he could
see into some of these worlds and I
think they're a fantastic tool as
psychedelics especially a her a tool
that can be used by not just the
psychonaut but the Philosopher's the
mystic and the scientist alike these are
something where we can find this strange
space and ask what what is it saying
about who we are and what we
as a creature in this world and what I
don't know there's some big questions
that I'm probably ranting and rambling a
little bit here but yeah well look it's
all very interesting I mean I think that
the place where we can fundamentally
agree is that honest conversations about
things that are powerful need to take
place I mean I can't think of anything
more necessary than that really well but
we don't talk about religion and
politics at the table right yeah that's
difficult for me because I've always
been someone to talk about that at the
table I think is the most important
conversations we should be shouldn't be
forgetting them and people just do that
for the sake of keeping face with their
crazy uncle or whatever well I can tell
you whatever could motivate someone to
try and have conversations about
psychedelic experience is I think a deep
point of connection between people even
if it might not be the easiest thing to
put into words you know there are
certain states of experience therein
that are self-evidently important enough
to attempt to relate cohesively to your
life and the lives of people around you
as it's just a very as a very basic
thing but I am concerned about I don't
know I always have this idea I'm
classically British in this way and it's
partly because I heard a international
relations lecture I had in 2010 say that
the English way in his version of
International Relations I was always
trying to find the middle road but for
me I have I think quite I think it's
quite important to keep psychedelics
as a broad domain of inquiry that is
interdisciplinary and that doesn't get
too attached to one or another political
motive or religion necessarily don't box
that up as something that's only helpful
for therapy even though that's seemingly
the the most appropriate way to get
psychedelics with an evidence-based
approach behind it through the door so
it's important to kind of to be able to
have a conversation about some of these
things without lots of the other
problems that we might have to take
certain broad economic or ideological
positions about even though there are of
course interesting reasons to try and
bring some of these things together it
is something that I do have a bit of
animosity BIA okay yeah or just a bit of
concern about I'm trying to turn a
figure that what you're saying is
something that I'm I feel concerned
about and I think a lot of other people
feel concerned about too because if you
do change the status quo which is
prohibition and I think that does need
to change because I've heard too many
stories of people's lives being torn
apart by prohibition and I think
sometimes just just on that point
sometimes people say oh we need to keep
it this way because it kind of keeps it
secret and we don't want the mainstream
to get a blah blah blah all of this sort
of stuff and I'd say yeah I sort of see
your point but you know you you're
killing off half you know a bunch of
people you forgetting the the less
advantaged people you're forgetting I
guess that you might be in a more
privileged position or maybe you just
haven't run up against some of the
problems that other people run up
against so I think prohibition has to go
but I mean with the medical thing that's
going on one of the the fears that I
have is that could it get locked into
this idea as this kind of I mean I don't
think it will because I think the
experience itself sort of necessitates
breaking out of the box in many ways but
then there's a lot of power in that and
people could put that back into the box
but yeah it is a bit you don't want to
it being caught up in that frame workers
or you know this is a medicine for sick
people and then sick people are people
that we can measure certain sicknesses
of and you know that sort of thing and
then you wouldn't want something like an
alcohol or tobacco industry for
psychedelics because then it becomes all
this like lobbying crony capitalist
nonsense that goes on which is the crazy
game we're playing now I mean how would
you do it you don't want it just some of
the plays in in the u.s. like Santo
Daime a and you DV I don't know a whole
lot about them but something in me goes
well I wouldn't want to have to join
some religious group to be able to
experience these things either so yeah
what are we left with you almost have to
come up with some kind of benevolent in
inherently democratic organization whose
so goals and values are using the the
money that it gets from selling these
substances to just put back into itself
and build honorary places for people to
go into art or sit and like a secular
religion of sorts you know religion
without all the the hangups but then
does that then get that maybe I'm
missing my own hangups yeah it's a it's
a hard question absolutely I think that
is one of the questions I think about
Mohsen and ends up being the place where
a lot of conversations I have with
people that are interested in
psychedelics ends up going it's
fundamentally about what kind of
cultural structure allows the proper
integration of altered states of
consciousness into our current life and
that also has to take into account where
our current society is at and it seems
to me at least the main impetus of the
change towards nothing more than the
ability to engage honestly about altered
states of experience and how they relate
to meaning it needs to be one that
happens on an individual level I mean
because I do think that's just such a
massive danger with one particular
overarching system trying to set the
tone for how these experiences gets
created yeah absolutely
but nevertheless that the structure
there does well that you do need a
structure in order to orient I mean look
so this is I think a question that is
different religions have grappled with
and put rather mystically its what's the
appropriate hierarchical structure
between hell and heaven or from them or
from the man on the ground up to God you
know it might not be appropriate for I
mean it would it would be I think quite
ridiculous actually for us to go to
where we're at right now to suddenly
whoever our that 15 most important
people 24 most important people in
setting legalities in Australia if they
all just decided all right that's it all
psychedelics are legal and we're gonna
bloody fund it with two billion dollars
some ridiculous thought experiment all
of a sudden something changes tomorrow
and everyone can have access to these
things well I don't think we're ready
for that no and so threatened SETI right
absolutely absolutely but at the same
time without a proper degree of
democratization of the
path towards something that fills this
divine part of the human potential well
I mean there has to be an element of
democracy to that the path because if
there is such a thing as a pastor
divinity if just put in a very
metaphorical sense it's because every
human being has that in in their very
essence fundamentally and so to deny
that possibility to anybody is perhaps
one of the one of the greatest crimes
you could ever possibly do and is surely
the mark of a civilization in decay or
going the wrong way and there could be
many things that are that of course yeah
I mean I suppose that you know I've got
questions rumbling around my head of how
what prohibition is all about is it
really about the things that we've sort
of I mean it's obviously not the things
that are at the top level that we've
heard about and we know that it was used
for scapegoating a lot of the time but
there are other reasons as well I get
into this space where I have I'm still
skimming the tip of our iceberg on this
sort of information and and I think it
can seem to get very conspiratorial and
and bizarre soon so you know grain
assault here but the psychedelics didn't
get discovered this century or last
century it's not an experience that has
been unknown and even not to Western
civilization you you go back to the the
ancient Greeks and you might be familiar
with clack Eon and Aleph Seon mysteries
mysteries mysteries and some speculation
that there might have been some other
psychoactive compounds there and it
seems even that a lot of the alcoholic
who were supposed alcoholic drinks over
the many millennia had a whole range of
other plants in them with a whole range
of other things and we know that there
were orders of people the apothecaries
was sort of the more recent ones I
suppose but going back I can't think of
all the names of these people but there
is this this mixing of you know magic
and science are the same sort of thing
they came from the same places
philosophy and underpins these things
it's really all intertwined intertwine
yeah and it's only been recently we've
gone and divided them out but you know
it used to be the the magic people that
you would go to to help do these things
right
do you start to wonder because there's
so much power in it and power in these
altered experiences and and and you know
the mystery is is a powerful thing as
well if someone or group or maybe just
people just decided it independently of
each other kind of went hang on if we're
having people accessing these states
these places that we know about and if
they figure out how to use them
well then we might not be able to play
our little game about you know scarcity
and and making money from them and and
and you know essentially keeping you
your stock to make money from and grow
in power and that kind you know that's
that seems to be the game so I don't
know as I said grain of salt with this
with this stuff because I'm hobbling it
together from all sorts of places and I
listen to a lot of things and read a lot
of things and almost immediately forget
who the author was or whatever's I can't
quote it at you but there's something
something else something strange going
on and the worlds there unlocked by some
of the psychedelic experiences
especially things like DMT and you know
the the the whole acacia question in
Australia has me really like intrigued
and puzzled there seems to be something
deep in that because it's also a tree
that turns up in the Quran and the Torah
and you know in these ancient Abrahamic
texts where these people weren't the
dogmatic people we see today as the
majority of the followers of these
religions seems like these were you know
these were the the magic people the
mystics that the March either whatever
you want to call them who were having
these strange experiences and dreaming
whole new worlds and I think we might be
living in one of them hmm yeah
interesting well what would you say has
been the most impactful or strange
experience you've had with the
psychedelic of your choice there's been
a whole handful of strange ones trying
to remember them sometimes I feel like
is trying to remember a dream and
sometimes I'm bitten or slash slightly
suspicious of how well some people can
recollect certain psychedelic
experiences either they're really good
at remembering that or they're filling
in some gaps later when they're sober to
make it you know an Isis story to tell
so I've had a number of
interesting experiences or inspiring or
reverent in some way and some because
they were hellish and yeah I had had a
lesson to throw at me ah one that I was
quite fond of which was just rather
banal really but I think it was one of
the first times I'd had acid with some
friends and said a beach town and won't
sort of mentioned places but you know
got lots of lovely beaches around and we
just had a good night of what do we do I
found all the chairs in the house and
and and stacked them into one doorway
and it was very satisfied with that we
laughed at some hotdogs in some water
with one single piece of grated cheese
in there for inordinate amounts of time
we walked to the beach and found the
center of the universe it's on this
beach look well after you find the
cheese and the sausage then there was a
pterodactyl and I think that was pretty
much it well you know let me
let's flip the coin here I'm gonna read
out a passage that Carl Jung wrote in a
letter to Victor White and he wrote this
on the 10th of April 1954 is the LSD
drug you referring to mescaline it has
indeed very curious effects Vita aldous
huxley of which I know far too little I
don't know either
what its psychotherapeutic value with
neurotic or psychotic Patience's I only
know there's no point in wishing to know
more of the collective unconscious than
one gets through dreams and intuition
the more you know of it the greater and
heavier becomes your moral burden
because the unconscious contents
transform themselves into your
individual tasks and duties as soon as
they become conscious do you want to
increase loneliness and misunderstanding
do you want to find more and more
complications and increasing
responsibilities you get enough of it if
I once could say that I had done
everything I know I had to do then
perhaps I should realize a legitimate
need to take mescaline if I should take
it now I would not be at all sure that I
had not taken it out of idle curiosity I
should hate the thought that I had
touched on the sphere where the paint is
made that colours the world where the
light is created that makes shine the
splendor of the dawn the lines and
shapes of all form the sound that feels
the orbit the thought that illuminates
the darkness of the void there are some
impoverished creatures perhaps for whom
mescaline would be a heaven-sent gift
without a counter poison but I am
profoundly mistrustful of the pure gifts
of the gods you pay very dearly for them
this is not the point at all to know of
or about the unconscious nor does the
story end here on the contrary it is how
and where you begin the real quest if
you are too unconscious it is a great
relief to know a bit of the collective
unconscious but it soon becomes
dangerous to know more because one does
not learn at the same time how to
balance it through a conscious
equivalent that is the mistake Aldous
Huxley makes he does not know that he is
in the role of zarbor luring Sorcerer's
Apprentice who learned from his master
how to call the ghosts but did not know
how to get rid of them again yeah so the
reason that couple paragraphs there came
to mind I think
what young is getting out there is
perhaps it cuts very close to the core
of what the element of responsibility
that's incumbent on anyone who decides
they want to take a psychedelic
substance has to come to terms with you
know we've been talking about the fact
that these are if nothing else strange
and powerful things we're strange here
is the very essence of strange and
powerful is at least on the
psychological and perhaps spiritual
level the very essence of power and the
question then becomes if you have such
experiences you can't quite put into
words but feel somehow filled with a
sense of meaning to take or integrate
some of that experience into a life well
how do you go about doing that
what should you orient towards what kind
of life facilitates the integration of
some of these experiences now young of
course references here that the
collective unconscious and it's a vast
domain of study filled with the
requirement to have a real deep relation
to a kind of psychological symbolism and
an appreciation of the thematic content
that I think cuts at this area of
confusion about truth and where
something like the mystical parts of our
world might meet the scientific endeavor
and there's these strange things that
are brought together that pop up through
and from a place that we can construe as
the unconscious we could construe it as
the potential for human experience but
that they pop up in our experience and
they have the power in fact to orient
our action but also reveal how it is we
are already acting how we might be
relating to our parents or our friends
in a particular social environment how
that might relate to certain systems
that are mechanically involved in the
cycle of the world affairs
there can be an awareness of the of the
the power associated with what something
like a pure malevolent feeling is when
it's attached to someone who's animated
by a particular view of the world or a
particular ideology even though that
that person himself might think that
there might be the most benign person
maybe they are speaking purely
rationally and purely factually but in
actual fact it's it's somehow there's a
possession there there's so we almost
need to get into and I think I think
young sort of touched on that a bit what
was the the last or second last
paragraph again this is not the point at
all to know of or about the unconscious
nor does the story end here on the
contrary it is how and where you begin
the real quest if you are too
unconscious it's a great relief to know
a bit about the collective unconscious
but it soon becomes dangerous to know
more because one does not learn at the
same time how to balance it through a
conscious equivalent I think that on
that point it's one does not learn and I
mean we're in a different context now to
when Jung wrote this but not a hugely
different context and I do wonder about
this kind of you know I've been thinking
a lot about what is it that that sort of
fundamentally separates a lot of people
you know we have this left and right
wing supposedly in political thought and
we have conservative and progressive and
we love these dichotomies that we have
put it battle against each other but
what is it about the thinking because I
don't like the the left-right separation
because you can really you know if you
drill down into somebody you'll find
like a variety of views in there that
you could put in either one of those
counties so we're still not not thinking
about this thing in a way that's quite
coherent enough but then there's a lot
of people that don't like that you know
fundamentally we cannot know if the
sun's gonna rise tomorrow I can't even
remember the the philosophical Leggett's
Humes problem of induction yeah yeah
exactly the these sorts of things doubt
is inherent like change is the only
constant but that makes people
uncomfortable
and some people are quite comfortable in
putting that to the side putting the
discomfort of doubt to the
and just filling in a little little gap
and sitting with that but the
psychedelic to get the most out of it we
need to teach people how to critically
engage we can access these ultimately
bizarre strange amazing reverent worlds
that seem like these are the worlds of
the divine you know but what does that
mean when you've got to go to work
tomorrow to make sure that you can pay
your gas bill on Friday and so it can
get people unstuck and we do see people
become unstuck because of that and I
think that maybe it's important just now
to mention that all the great talk
that's been going on about psychedelics
in the media and about the medical
potential has raised the profile of
psychedelics in people's minds that
might not have heard about it before but
in a way that kind of concerns me we
have people that will spend thousands of
dollars traveling to the other side of
the world for what they think is an
authentic experience to go and sit with
shaman or suppose it's shaman in
whatever you know country and I it's
authentic sorry but why was living your
life not authentic I feel like we've
gone through this doublespeak thing
where we disconnecting more trying to
connect at the same time and losing
ourselves along the way because we're
forgetting that what's wrong with a
circus I see where you're going there I
mean I think there are perfectly good
reasons and I'm sure you agree that it's
perfectly good reasons to have an
experience say in Peru with shamans
there no no that's not the point you're
making but I think what might be the
attraction of this way is that well
there is a culture that has developed I
don't know if I can say this for the
purpose of being able to properly
integrate these sorts of experiences
right so in terms of a set and setting
that has worked for various indigenous
populations around the world that have
used different plant compounds to have
these sorts of experiences they
developed a way of relating to this that
seems to give them sustaining value in
their culture and it mean it's it's
understandable why people might feel
like they don't have access to a place
where they can authentically engage with
this stuff here but in principle in
principle it's it's apps you don't need
to go anywhere you've got everything you
need right here if only you were aware
of how properly to can
yourself which is no face of hard to get
information and I think this comes back
down to questions of authority and what
legitimacy is because legitimacy is this
funny word that pops up again in
discussing drug policy and looking at
the discussions in Parliament in
Victoria around the drug laws that we
have and why some of it is considered
illegitimate use to use an illicit
substance because there's no legitimate
purpose for it if there are a legitimate
purpose then it wouldn't be prohibited
would it right there's this strange sort
of things so people people want
legitimacy whatever this is though you
know they want that that's what they
think is the authenticity I think it's a
trick that's being played I think you
can make what's legitimate for you
although don't tell everybody because I
don't know what might just all break the
laws or whatever I don't know you have
precisely against the problem there
which is the fact that actually we are
doing as a society an awful lot of
things well despite the fact that we can
recognize a number of problems right
that could be so disastrous that our
civilization turns out to be absolutely
not
adaptive enough but at the same time and
you know for some people those problems
and for most of us really those problems
might be climate problems perhaps or the
development of weapons that are far too
powerful for us to use or the order
sequestering away of substances that
have actually always perhaps been
involved with an appropriate relation to
spirituality odd there could be a whole
a whole number of things but the fact is
that we are doing an awful lot of things
very well I think in different parts of
the world and I think that there are
clear and obvious positive sides to to
capitalism for instance which is in loot
yeah there's a positive and negative
side of the coin there's so many things
when you can dream an idea and say to
somebody hey I've got this idea it's
gonna be wicked you want to help me out
with it that's capitalism in brilliant
action right there but when you've got
people saying I want to maintain my
profit margin so you politician friend
can you make some regulations that block
out other competitors from competing
against me or make my product the
you know give it some special place
that's crony capitalism that's still
capitalism but it's people using how we
operate our social networks how we as a
human being operate in the human world
in the meat space to our advantage
we're always of course going to do that
but it's where these systems come undone
yeah to tie this back into a broadly
Union perspective
young of course being concerned with
delving into our past and the
development and the evolution of themes
and patterns of action lenses of
perception that have evolved or have
co-evolved with human beings and their
particular methods of adaptation to the
world the fact is that there's an awful
lot that we come pre-built with in our
bodies you know there's a cognitive
potential we have our culture itself to
me it's intertwined with biology and
always informing each other and you
can't really pull them entirely apart
from one another and there's always
parts of it that need to be updated but
the fact is that there's a core to what
we are that we come into the world with
that has worked insofar as its sustained
life for many many many millions of
years and you can track it back I think
it's real it's relevant to track it back
far beyond and far before the time we
are human beings so the idea might be to
recognize that there's lots of what
we're doing in the world that if we
suddenly come to realize it while it
seems so far and all of a sudden I
didn't realize it was so strange that I
was complicit in some sort of weird
maybe I wasn't aware of how the element
of sexuality crept into how I dressed or
how I treated different sorts of people
or how having a sort of imitation like
respect for an older person made me act
a different way around them and perhaps
I felt intimidated by them in some
respect or challenge and that made me
have frustrated but hey maybe there's a
there's a positive value to be
recognised in in respecting somebody and
and positive value to recognize that
well it's the flip side of the coin you
you have a system or a strut
Society on one hand it can tend towards
tyranny on the other hand it's a
protective space that allows the
possibility for individuals to develop
now what those particular structures
might be need to develop mmm but the
fact that there still needs to be a
structure and that it can always tend
towards the negative as well as it can
the positive is sort of like an eternal
thing to me but the question is what is
worth saving so I guess just to tie this
back into the concerns I have about when
psychedelics get tacked on to too many
other places of discussion or movements
it's like change is necessary but it's
probably very rare that any one
individual knows what the hell to do
about a complex issue fully they might
really understand a small part of it and
then it becomes about how do you
appropriately get experts together and
communicate in a way that you know in
this or that and that and that's that
it's just that we need to move slowly
but we need to move purposefully I will
totally agree with you that there are
certain like the incarceration that
comes along with prohibition and these
sorts of things like there are egregious
wrongs that are still being done to
people that's the sort of stuff that I
think it just needs to be cut out you
know and it's that sort of activism if
you like that I could get behind but
it's a very it's very low-hanging fruit
in a sense it's decriminalization
essentially of a personal use doesn't
fix any of the market issues which is
where the complex questions come come
into it but you know if you just had
decriminalization of all drugs really
but coarse of psychedelics and at least
you're not punishing people for small
amounts of of these substances and
running them through a system that's
likely to create far more trauma than
the drug itself and then it can open up
this space to at least begin more honest
discussions with people and give people
who are just you know because there
there is that tendency among some people
to choose to take a drug as an act of
rebellion of sorts but not sort of
rational rebellion just sort of like
they're like given the bird to everyone
I'm gonna do this because it's the wrong
thing and you told me not to you know I
don't know if you've had friends like
that before but I've got some friends
who have absolutely engaged in whatever
action it was like a friend of mine in
in high school voted for one nation for
the sole reason that everybody was like
are one nation of shit don't vote for
nations I had no idea about politics
he was just like that's the thing that
everyone's telling me not to do so I'm
gonna do it like well that's the classic
human thing right yeah another bit of
low-hanging fruit if we could only
achieve this let's get to a point where
it's not considered the pinnacle of the
rebellious thing to go out and take some
sort of illicit drug you know because
there you're not going to have any of
the appropriate set in setting or almost
certainly when it's not going to be part
of a culture that enables a proper
integration of some of these experiences
I mean we're never going to stamp out of
human beings especially in the
adolescent phase to do exactly what
they're not supposed to do or at least
have to deal with that that's part of
the beauty of human beings as well I
mean you want to properly adapt that
within yourself and find the appropriate
boundaries to push in your own life and
propria areas of uncertainty to play
around with you know not advocating for
like ridiculous behavior that's puts
other people or yourself in danger
throwing as fiery flares into groups of
a teenager so these questions they all
seem to come come back to I don't think
I can get too much further than just
attempting to have honest conversations
about some of this stuff and then to try
and to try and relate it to some
metaphysical issues and some scientific
issues I find it really difficult though
because this you know we met for mere
moments a few months ago but otherwise
we've never spoken before and it can be
so challenging to try and take
everything all the intellectual baggage
that I come to a conversation with and
all the terms that I think I'm more or
less understand and more or less kind of
cobble together cohesively and then and
then find the appropriate place to build
a bridge between when you're sitting and
then go okay what are the things that
are the sort of binding bridge making
actually wait patterns of action that we
can both get on board with and we're at
that level of I think that first
principles level of just sorting out how
to have difficult conversations about
strange things in a way that doesn't
immediately sequester who you're talking
to
into some ideological box that therefore
means they believe all of this and
that's not going to change and that
means they're going to take this
position this all of a sudden no
dialogue I think as I've been saying one
of them one of the exciting things about
psychedelics as well as the issue of
climate change there are two things that
have this bridge making potential
between human beings and I would like to
see I could see that being leveraged for
a very positive purpose you know people
always talk about the fact that human
beings are sort of tribal creatures and
we could also come at it from a
psychological perspective but there's a
sort of there's a unifying element to
the other you know you can band together
and work cooperatively if you've all if
you've got this enemy now the challenge
is if we're gonna take that as a model
what is the appropriate other to sort of
orient in everybody it was gonna be
aliens isn't is that still the
prevailing theme or no sorry we need a
devil or a Hell or yes yeah you're right
people do like to gather around that and
have that other but I just wanted to
touch on something quickly you were just
mentioning and it's the word psychedelic
is a word that was coined by his name
now is in the conversation with the
phrase was to fathom helps or angelic
just take a pinch of psychedelic and
it's not about linguistic standards it's
not a properly constructed word it's a
cobbled together of two terms and it's
meant to mean to to manifest mind
Humphry Osmond Humphry Osmond thank you
we've ended up with this word by sort of
historical anomaly now as a lot of
things aren't come along and happen but
the word psychedelic means to manifest
what's in the mind but that's all we
ever do all we're ever doing is
manifesting and creating in this world
what was in our mind we can't build
towers we can't build Road cities boats
aeroplanes without having first thought
of it and started to juggle down some
ideas so in that way it's it's it's a
funny it's a funny thing that we've
ended up calling these substances
psychedelic when it seems that we are by
our very nature psychedelic creatures
and maybe this other in that we do I
think is part of its necessary part of
the biological process we've got a
limited we're a limited system in terms
of what the human being actually is
we've got a body that's yay big we've
got so much energy we've got a brain
that can do this that and the other we
have certain
cities that we reach I can't know
intimately seven billion people I don't
know the emotional worlds that they live
in the history it's a huge task and we
come up with all kinds of psychological
shortcuts to do that and I think that's
where we get a lot of these archetypes
and these symbols and stereotypes and
all these ways that we whittle down the
information into small amounts where we
can then make assumptions about the
person that we're talking to as he said
you know somebody says this idea and go
well that's the series of ideas that
they believe and we won't bother talking
to them anymore because now they're the
other that other who fits in that
category and I don't know they're just
the crazy people or whatever but that a
lot of that has to do with just this
kind of inherent metaphysical hubris of
sorts that we have where we say to
ourselves that we are this this grand
thing especially in the Abrahamic
traditions you know where we're meant to
be like the reflection of God on earth
but this kind of from what I read quite
a selfish and vengeful God a lot of the
time in an Old Testament at least and
then even in the New Testament the whole
thing is a bloody human sacrifice cult
that the only way that we can have
redemption in the glorious paradise of
afterlife is by accepting the murder of
a human being for something that I'm not
sure how we did why that was a wrong
thing in the first place yeah it's
bizarre that separation but I think that
sometimes we need to remind ourselves
when we're making those assumptions
about people and actually maybe that's a
challenge I can say if you listening
right now whenever you are talking to
somebody and you're starting to make a
lot of assumptions especially on the
internet remind yourself that this is an
abstract version that you're talking to
you're not talking to that person you're
talking to what you think that person is
in your head and in in some ways that's
how we're never ever truly connected and
why we're all truly sort of alone in
this kind of dark nihilistic place but
it's not not trying to say it in in that
kind of way I'm I'm just trying to
foster a reminder that although we are
only ever going to be whatever we are in
in our brains we do have this ability to
connect but we also have the ability to
remember the limitations of what that
connection are and when we understand
our limitations I think understanding
limitations is just as important as
trying to break through things because
without understanding where the barriers
are you can think you've broken through
it but you'll just be tricking yourself
somehow you know thinking this this kind
of thinking that we have in neoliberal
economic
thought at the moment at the heart of
our our economy is that we can just grow
and grow forever and I've people had
more choices we'd have better outcomes
because more choices lead to better
outcomes is bullshit more choices don't
lead to better outcomes because people
get confused because people have too
much information they don't know what to
do with it and I think that's what it is
for a lot of us a lot of the time that
we have too much information we don't
know what to do with it but people love
to pretend they do people love to you
know suggest that they've got to worked
out which I know is kind of a conundrum
in itself because I'm saying I've got it
worked out by saying that I don't have a
worked out but well I mean part of the
process is talking about how you don't
have it worked out that's the important
thing there for me let me see I it seems
to me like a pretty good place to bring
things to a close don't know about you
is there anything you want to say to
listeners about how they can get in
touch with you or listen to in
psychedelia and we've been through it a
little bit but don't know if you want
yeah sure um well first up I'll give a
plug to the Australian psychedelic
society it's a recently formed
I've been running about one and a half
years now organization we run relatively
regular events for the most part we've
been doing sort of movie events and
discussion events where we'll get
somebody to talk about a particular
topic had music as well and now we're
also starting to do more intimate events
integration circles where people can
come and there will be some experienced
people there sometimes experience in
terms of these people are psychologists
or psychiatrists who then you can talk
about your experience whether it was a
difficult or just a beautiful experience
and you just want to talk about it with
like-minded people just check out the
the Australian psychedelic Society on
Facebook or psychedelic society calm day
you we're going to be updating websites
and all sorts of stuff as the year
progresses so I think through this
organization we're creating legitimacy
for the discussion around psychedelics
we're saying you know we're not a place
don't try and source drugs from us for
like just don't that's not part of the
creating of legitimacy we're trying to
create legitimacy around the discussions
and and be serious about it and not fob
it off like some pop culture joke which
is how psychedelics are mostly taken in
the mainstream at the moment it's just
sort of a you know joke about Pink Floyd
and rainbows would
so yeah please do check out the
Australian psychedelic Society we have
chapters in Melbourne and Sydney and
fledgling chapters in Adelaide Brisbane
and Perth and four in psyckadeli it's a
weekly radio show it's on three CR on
Sundays you can listen live or three CRA
you and find in psychedelia under the
program pages there and you know we just
covering all things drugs every week
talking about drugs every week a wide
variety of things don't get to delve
into things quite as deep as we have
here which I love by the way thank you
very much for thank you for coming it's
been a pleasure it's not something we
get to do on that show because we're
trying to turn three things quickly and
we have in mind as well then we're
talking to an audience that might not be
interested in esoteric
sidelines well I imagine we're gonna do
a few more of these in the future and I
look forward to those but until then
it's been a pleasure thank you very much
thank you for having me too much
[Music]
thank you for listening if you'd like to
hear more of these conversations and to
stay in touch about events planned later
this year in Melbourne please do like
the Facebook page follow voice Club
underscore on Twitter subscribe on
YouTube that we videos soon and most
other places you usually listen to your
podcasts best of all sign up to the
mailing list via the connect tab at
voice for our comm and if you found this
valuable please consider sharing or
leaving a review you can also support
voice club on patreon with a monthly
subscription links to which can be found
on voice club comm and in the
description from the 7th of May 2018
onwards there is so much more to come
all right we'll see you then
[Music]